scrumalliance.org 2017-02-15

# Privacy Policy - Scrum Alliance

Home » 

Welcome to the Scrum Alliance Web site www.scrumalliance.org (the "Site") provided to you by Scrum Alliance, Inc., its affiliate and subsidiary companies ("SA", "us" or "we"). Your privacy is important to us, and our policy is simple: SA will collect no personally identifiable information about you when you visit the Site unless you choose to provide that information.

This Privacy Statement addresses SA’s practices regarding information collected only directly through or from the Site – it does not address or govern any information gathering, use, or dissemination practices related to information collected from the visitor (sometimes referred to as "you" or "your") other than directly through or from the Site, such as from telephone, facsimile, postal mail, personal delivery, third parties, or other or additional offline means or media. This Privacy Statement is incorporated into SA's Terms of Service by reference, as if set forth fully therein, which must be reviewed and accepted by you.

##  1\. Collection of personal information from site visitors

Except as specifically set forth herein, SA may collect or track (1) the home server domain names, date and time of your visit, type of computer, the originating IP address, files downloaded, search engine used, operating system, and type of Web browser of visitors to the Site, (2) the e-mail addresses of visitors that communicate with SA via e-mail, (3) information knowingly provided by the visitor in online forms, registration or membership forms, contest entries, surveys, e-mail, and other online avenues (including, without limitation, demographic and personal profile data), (4) aggregate and user-specific information regarding which pages Site visitors access. Specifically, and in order to register as a SA member or to be certified under SA’s certification programs, you may be required to provide additional personal information such as your name, address and other relevant personal information in your member profile (“Profile”) in order to obtain membership or certification. If you do not wish to provide such information to the Site, you will be unable to gain membership status.

SA may place Internet “cookies” on your hard drive. Internet cookies are small amounts of data that contain a unique identifier that many web sites frequently send to your web browser to be stored on your computer’s hard drive in order to save data about you, such as your name, password, user-name, screen preferences, and the pages of a site you have viewed. When you revisit the Site, SA may recognize you by your Internet cookies and customize your experience accordingly. You may decline Internet cookies by using the appropriate feature of your Web browser software, if available.

SA may use Google Analytics or a similar service to gather, store, and track certain information related to your visit to and activity on the Site.

When a visitor performs a search within the Site, SA may record information identifying the visitor or linking the visitor to the search performed and recording information related to the search request.

##  2\. Use of personal data collected

Personal data collected by SA may be used by SA for many reasons, for example, for editorial and feedback purposes, for marketing and promotional purposes, for a statistical analysis of users’ behavior, for product development, for content improvement, for fulfillment of a requested transaction or recordkeeping, or to customize the content and layout of the Site. Aggregate data on visitors’ home servers may be used for internal purposes, and individually identifying information, such as names, postal and e-mail addresses, phone numbers, and other personal information which visitors voluntarily provide to SA may be added to SA’s databases and used for future calls and mailings regarding Site updates, new products and services, and upcoming events. The general information gathered from a visitor is used to improve the content of Site and the quality of our service, and is not shared with or sold to other organizations for commercial purposes, except if it becomes necessary to share information to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of the Scrum Alliance Terms of Service, or as otherwise required by law.

As a benefit to SA members and individuals certified by SA, SA will include a member’s name and relevant personal information in his or her Profile. Each individual’s Profile is accessible through the Site. If you are or become a member, You agree that your name and your SA certification information may be made publicly available on the Site. You have the right to specify whether certain other personal information in your Profile is publicly available or not. From time to time, we may need to contact you for membership-related activities (e.g., renewal notices, etc.). You agree that we may use your personal information for such membership-related contacts with you. We may also desire to contact you for market research purposes or to provide you with marketing information we think would be of particular interest. You will have the option of not being contacting by us and opting-out of such contacts by setting the appropriate option in your Profile.

##  3\. Disclosure of personal data to third parties

SA will not sell, rent, or lease any individually identifiable information to others without your permission. Unless we have your permission or are required by law, we will only share the personal data you provide to us with other SA entities and/or business partners who are acting on our behalf to help us provide you with our products and services. Such SA entities and/or business partners are governed by our privacy policies with respect to the use of this data and are bound by this Privacy Policy and applicable confidentiality agreements.

Aggregate data on visitors’ home servers may be provided to third parties such as marketing firms.

Identifiable and non-identifiable visitor information and data may be disclosed or distributed to another party with which SA enters or reasonably may enter into a corporate transaction, such as, for example, a merger, consolidation, acquisition, or asset purchase, or to a third party pursuant to a subpoena, court order, or other form of legal process, in response to a request by or on behalf of any local, state, federal, or other government agency, department, or body, whether or not pursuant to a subpoena, court order, or other form of legal process, or if determined by SA in its sole judgment that such disclosure or distribution is appropriate to protect the life, health, or property of SA or any other person or entity.

While SA may undertake efforts to see that any third party to which SA shares, rents, sells, or otherwise discloses personal data is under a contractual obligation to use the personal data solely for the purposes for which the data was disclosed, such third parties are independent third parties over which SA exercises no control. SA is not responsible for, and will not be liable for, the conduct, actions, omissions, or information handling or dissemination practices of third parties.

##  4\. Links to other sites

This Site may contain links to other World Wide Web sites or advertisements for or placed by third parties. SA is not responsible for the privacy practices of such Web sites, advertisers, or third parties, or for the content of such sites or advertisements. It is possible that these links or advertisements, themselves, may be used by third parties or others to collect personal or other information about Site visitors. It is your sole obligation to review and understand the privacy practices and policies of these other Web sites and of these advertisers and third parties.

##  5\. Security measures and communicating with SA

SA has implemented security features that are designed to prevent the loss, misuse, alteration or unauthorized release of or access to personal information provided to us. However, the confidentiality of any communication or material transmitted to or from SA via this Site or e-mail cannot be and is not guaranteed. In addition, you understand that the technical processing and transmission of the Site content may be transferred unencrypted and involve (a) transmissions over various networks; and (b) changes to conform and adapt to technical requirements of connecting networks or devices. Accordingly, SA is not responsible for the security of information transmitted via the Internet. Instead of communicating with SA via e-mail (info@scrumalliance.org) or the Internet, visitors can contact SA by regular mail at P.O. Box 40097, Indianapolis, IN 46240-0097.

##  6\. Comments, notices and user content

Any material or comments, including Profiles, posted to any of our Web pages are public. Please refer to Section 4 of the Terms and Conditions for further detail concerning User Content and other materials submitted to the Site. As such, SA assumes no liability for the accuracy of such information, no duty to update or correct such information, and no liability for such communications arising under the laws of copyright, libel, privacy, obscenity, or otherwise.

##  7\. Opt-Out right

Except as necessary for SA to provide the services, information, or products requested by a visitor, the visitor may opt out of having his or her personally identifiable information, which has been voluntarily provided to SA through online forms, membership or registration forms and Profiles, contest entries, surveys, e-mail, or another online avenue, prospectively retained by SA, used by SA for secondary purposes, or disclosed by SA to third parties, by contacting SA via postal mail, e-mail, or telephone at the addresses set out above. (This does not apply to collection of the type of Web browser of the visitor to the Site or to non-identifiable visitor information provided or collected.)

##  8\. Privacy of children

The Site is not intended for children under the age of 13. It does not knowingly collect personal information online from visitors in this age group. All users must be at least 18 years of age in order to use the Site.

##  9\. Access to and ability to correct personal data

Upon a visitor’s request via postal mail, e-mail, or telephone, SA will provide to the visitor a summary of any personally identifiable information retained by SA regarding the visitor that has been voluntarily provided by the visitor to SA through online forms, membership or registration forms, contest entries, surveys, e-mail, or another online avenue. A visitor may modify, correct, change or update his or her personally identifiable information by contacting SA via postal mail, e-mail, or telephone at the addresses or numbers above.

##  10\. Right to change privacy statement

SA may change this Privacy Statement at any time. It is the obligation of users returning to the Site to learn of changes to the Privacy Statement since their last visit. Any change to this Privacy Statement shall be effective as to any visitor who has visited the Site before the change was made.

##  11\. Your California privacy rights

If you are a California resident, California Civil Code Section 1798.83 provides you with the right to request certain information regarding disclosure of your personal information to third parties for direct marketing purposes, including a description of the categories of personal information disclosed. In order to obtain such information, please email your request to [info @ scrumalliance.org] or write us at the address below.

##  12\. Contact information

Scrum Alliance, Inc., is located in Westminster, Colorado, USA. Any questions, comments, or suggestions regarding this Privacy Policy should be provided to the Administrator as follows:

By e-mail: info@scrumalliance.org

By postal mail: 7401 Church Ranch Blvd. #210, Westminster, CO 80021 USA

This Privacy Statement is effective March 15, 2011 Last updated: March 15, 2011

Copyright © 2015 Scrum Alliance, Inc.; All rights reserved.
